<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on TMC - 11 Digital Tech</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on TMC - 11 Digital Tech</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><atom:link href="https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Software</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/software/</guid><description>To start using Kivy to develop apps, you will need to:
Open the Company Portal: Find and install Visual Studio Code (NOT Visual Studio Community): Find and install Python (3.9):
Open Visual Studio Code and install the Python Extension</description></item><item><title>1. Hello World</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/helloworld/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/helloworld/</guid><description>Taken from prosperocoder.com
Hello World – A Basic Kivy App Well, we’re going to write a basic Kivy app that will display the Hello World text. In Kivy, like in many other GUI libraries and frameworks, static text is usually displayed in a label. In Kivy we call simple GUI elements like labels, buttons, sliders, check boxes, etc. widgets, although widgets don’t have to be simple at all and you can create your own widgets, which we are going to do later.</description></item><item><title>2. Kv Files</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/kvfiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/kvfiles/</guid><description>Taken from prosperocoder.com
Our program contains just one widget, the label. This is all as far as presentation is concerned. We’ll move that part to a new file and leave the rest in the main.py file. So, after we remove the presentation part from the main.py, as well as the comments to make the file clear and transparent, this is what we’ll have:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 # We&amp;#39;re using Kivy, so we&amp;#39;ll need the kivy module import kivy # We need the App class.</description></item><item><title>3. Label Properties</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/labels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/labels/</guid><description>Taken from prosperocoder.com
Here’s the code again.
The Python file:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 File name: main.py import kivy from kivy.app import App from kivy.uix.button import Label class HelloWorldApp(App): def build(self): return Label() if __name__ == &amp;#39;__main__&amp;#39;: HelloWorldApp().run() and the kv file: 1 2 3 4 # File name: helloworld.kv &amp;lt;Label&amp;gt;: text: &amp;#39;Hello World!&amp;#39; This program displays a label. The label has a text property.</description></item><item><title>4. Buttons</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/buttons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/buttons/</guid><description>Taken from prosperocoder.com
A Button Widget is Basically a Label… In Kivy the Button class inherits from Label, so they have the same properties in common, plus the button has some extra functionality. In particular they share the text property. Let’s modify our main.py and helloworld.kv files so that our program displays a button widget instead of a label. First, let the changes be as few as possible. Here’s the main.</description></item><item><title>Flowcharts</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/flowcharts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/flowcharts/</guid><description>Flowcharts are a visual representation of program flow. A flowchart normally uses a combination of blocks and arrows to represent actions and sequence. Blocks typically represent actions. The order in which actions occur is shown using arrows that point from statement to statement. Sometimes a block will have multiple arrows coming out of it, representing a step where a decision must be made about which path to follow.
Start and End symbols are represented as rounded rectangles, usually containing the word &amp;ldquo;Star&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;End&amp;rdquo;, but can be more specific such as &amp;ldquo;Power Robot Off&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Stop All Motors&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Programming Constructs</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/constructs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/gettingStarted/constructs/</guid><description>Programs are designed using common building blocks. These building blocks, known as programming constructs (or programming concepts), form the basis for all programs.
There are three basic building blocks to consider:
sequence is the order in which instructions occur and are processed selection determines which path a program takes when it is running iteration is the repeated execution of a section of code when a program is running Sequence Sequence is the order in which programming statements are executed.</description></item></channel></rss>