<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kivy Layout Types on TMC - 11 Digital Tech</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/</link><description>Recent content in Kivy Layout Types on TMC - 11 Digital Tech</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><atom:link href="https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Float Layout</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/floatlayout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/floatlayout/</guid><description>A FloatLayout with a Button What we are going to do now is write code that uses a FloatLayout with a text input and a custom button in it. To demonstrate how the properties used for sizing and positioning work, though, let’s use just the button first.
The size_hint and pos_hint Properties This time we’re going to use the size_hint property instead of size to set the widget size.</description></item><item><title>ScreenManager</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/screenmanager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/screenmanager/</guid><description> Using more than one screen Watch the following video to learn how you can use more than one screen in your app.
Include the following 1 2 from kivy.lang import Builder from kivy.uix.screenmanager import ScreenManager How it fits together</description></item><item><title>Page Layouts</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/pagelayouts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/pagelayouts/</guid><description>The PageLayout works in a different manner from other layouts. It is a dynamic layout, in the sense that it allows flipping through pages using its borders. The idea is that its components are stacked in front of each other, and we can just see the one that is on top. PageLayout is similar to pages of a copy like that we can move/change the pages right or left.
The PageLayout class is used to create a simple multi-page layout, in a way that allows easy flipping from one page to another using border.</description></item><item><title>More Layouts</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/morelayouts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/morelayouts/</guid><description>Relative Layout RelativeLayout works pretty much like FloatLayout and the difference will be clear only later when we embed it in another layout. Here’s a simple example with a RelativeLayout and just one button in it. The button should be positioned at the fixed coordinates 0, 0 and occupy about a third of the available space in both horizontal and vertical direction.
Here’s the Python code: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 import kivy from kivy.</description></item><item><title>Embedding Layouts</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/embedlayouts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit11/appdev/layouts/embedlayouts/</guid><description>FloatLayouts and RelativeLayouts inside GridLayout As mentioned in the previous part, the FloatLayout and the RelativeLayout are pretty similar. The difference is that with the FloatLayout the coordinates are not relative to the position of the layout, whereas with RelativeLayout they are. Here’s a simple demonstration. We’ll use a GridLayout and embed four other layouts in it, two FloatLayouts and two RelativeLayouts. Here’s the Python code:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 import kivy from kivy.</description></item></channel></rss>